Mss.Ms.Coll.95 Mss.Ms.Coll.95
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Research Subjects (Box 19-85)
  - General Anthropology and Linguistics (Box 26-31)
    - Cultural and Natural Areas of Native North America (map), 1939, 1952; 2 items; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box 27)
      Also includes National Geographic map of North America.
    - Noun Incorporation in American Languages, n.d.; 1 item; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960 (Box 27)
      Photocopy of paper from XVI Internationaler Amerikanisten-Kongress.
    - Names from the history of child language research, n.d.; 2 pages; Leopold, W. F. (Box 28)
      Extract of names and dates from the named publication.
    - Library of Congress, 1972-1974, n.d.; 1.0 folder (Box 28)
      Includes "Information for Readers" booklet; call slip requests; notes; etc.
    - Primate Vocalizations and Human Linguistic Ability, 1968; 1 item; Lieberman, Philip (Box 28)
      Offprint from The Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, Vol. 44.
    - Linguistic Analysis, n.d.; 1 notebook (3 folders) (Box 28)
    - Abstracts submitted for annual meeting, 1958, n.d.; ca. 75 pages; Linguistic Society of America. (Box 28)
      Abstracts submitted by numerous individuals for LSA meeting.
    - The Northern Gateway: A History of Lake Champlain, 1939; 1 item; Lonergan, Carroll Vincent, b. 1916 (Box 28)
    - The Narration from Mt. Defiance, 1952; 1 item; Lonergan, James M. (Box 28)
    - Agreement Concerning Publication of Doctor's Dissertation, 1949; 1 item; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      FGL's agreement from Yale University.
    - Anthropology 43 Exam, n.d.; 1 item; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Exam for Anthropology 43.
    - [Classification of Languages], [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 28)
    - Ethnology: Art, n.d.; 3 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Handwritten bibliography and notes on art.
    - Ethnology: Bibliography, n.d.; 62 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Handwritten bibliographical notes on various topics.
    - Ethnology: Economics and Property, 2 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Handwritten notes on property and economics.
    - Ethnology: Introduction, n.d.; 1 item; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Handwritten notes for introduction.
    - Ethnology: Inventions and Technology, 7 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Handwritten notes on technology and subsistence; typed document, "Inventions."
    - Ethnology: Mochica, n.d.; 1 item; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Summary of "The Origin of man according to the Indians of the Coast of Peru" from Raimondi, El Peru, Vol. 2, 1876.
    - Ethnology: Northwest Coast, n.d.; 1 item; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Typed notes, "Art of the Northwest Coast of America."
    - Ethnology: Outlines for Courses and Text, 14 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Notes for an ethnology text; notes for ethnology courses.
    - Ethnology: Personality and Culture, 3 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Notes for courses; includes typed document by Anthony F. C. Wallace, "Some Psychological Determinants of Culture Change in an Iroquoian Community."
    - Ethnology: Slides, n.d.; 1 item; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Slide logs for various Native American groups and geographical areas.
    - Ethnology: Social Organization, 1951, n.d.; 2 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Short note on Tuareg; article on fraternity initiation from Time (March 5, 1951).
    - Ethnology: Student Reports, n.d.; 8 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Notes on various topics, authors unidentified; typed document by F. W. Shepard, "Notes on the Social Structure of the Balinese."
    - Ethnology: Systems of Knowledge, 1956, n.d.; 3 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Handwritten notes on science; article from Time (May 14, 1956) on measuring the circumference of the earth.
    - Ethnology: Theory, n.d.; 10 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Handwritten notes and bibliographical items on theory and method.
    - Field Methods and Techniques in Linguistics, ca. 40 pp; 3 items; 2 folders; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Notes, drafts, etc. From folder: "VF paper." Includes 3 offprints from Anthropology Today.
    - Indian Language Notes from [Morris] Swadesh Courses, ca. 60 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 28)
      Includes "A Method for Phonetic Accuracy and Speed" by MS.
    - Instructions for installing and using MAYACAL software, 1 item; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 28)
      Instructions for installing and using his MAYACAL software.
    - Language and Culture, 1969, n.d.; ca. 230 pages; 2 folders; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 29)
      Drafts of chapters for a large work. From folder "FGL Manuscripts on Linguistics General History"; photocopy of FGL's article from Language and Philosophy.
    - Language notes from University of Wisconsin days, ca. 60 pcs.; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 29)
      Various notes, paradigms, etc., including Old Irish.
    - Library, n.d.; 1 item; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 29)
      Listing of some journals and books belonging to FGL.
    - Linguistics, n.d.; 3 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 29)
      Typed manuscript with carbon copy.
    - Linguistics and Cultural Anthropology, 9 pages; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 29)
      Author's proofs. From folder: "UNPUB-UCLA CONF. 196_".
    - Linguistics and Psychology, 1963; 2 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 29)
      Offprints from Sigmund Koch, ed., Psychology: A Study of a Science.
    - MA Diploma, 1946; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 29)
      Lounsbury's masters degree diploma from the University of Wisconsin.
    - Map locating FGL's residence, n.d.; 10 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 29)
    - Methods and Course Progression, Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 29)
      Offprint from The Teaching of Linguistics in Anthropology.
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1952, n.d.; 72 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 29)
      Includes: Short autobiography of Mary Williams (Shawnee) probably in Shawnee without translation; clippings on Iroquois healing ceremony, family dispute between a Hopi and his Mohawk brother-in-law, poverty, and New Yorker cartoons; etc.
    - Notes on talk by Noam Chomsky, "A Transformational Approach to Syntax", n.d.; 2 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 29)
      Handwritten notes and typed version.
    - Obituary of Fremont Lounsbury, n.d.; 1 item; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 29)
      Handwritten copy.
    - Obituary of Thomas H. Lounsbury, n.d.; 1 item; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 29)
    - On the Classification and Use of Phonological Data, 25 pages; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 29)
      From folder: "Paper for Twaddell."
    - One Hundred Years of Anthropological Linguistics, 1968, n.d.; ca. 450 pages; 4 folders; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 29)
      Notes, drafts, etc. From Group: "Working Papers for Essay... [folder title]"; photocopy of FGL's article from J. O. Brew, ed., One Hundred Years of Anthropology.
    - Paper on Genetic Classification, n.d.; ca. 50 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 30)
      Outline, drafts, etc. From folder: "Paper: Clfn and Hist Rlns."
    - Paper on language for Archeological Society, 1945, n.d.; 16 pages; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 30)
      Drafts, etc. Included letter to Robert E. Ritzenthaler from Frank Koyatch regarding the origin of some bones.
    - Paper on Perception, n.d.; ca. 45 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 30)
      Original and carbon of typed manuscript.
    - Recordings -- Iroquois and Bororo, 4.0 p.; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 30)
      From folder: "Cherokee Phonology"
    - Similarity and Contiguity Relations in Language and in Culture, 1 item; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 30)
      Offprint from unidentified source.
    - Smithsonian Notes, 1962-1967, n.d.; 10 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 30)
      Notes on organization, etc. of the Office of Anthropology Archives; lists of manuscripts in the collection for Caddo, Karok, and Tsimshian; personnel requirements; etc.
    - Swadesh lecture notes, n.d.; 1 item; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 30)
      [Morris] Swadesh lecture notes on grammar.
    - Talk on Anthropological Linguistics, n.d.; ca. 80pages; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 30)
      Notes, drafts. From folder: "AAA, Washington mtg, 1967."
    - Teyutatyesvni takhwa, 1966; 6.0 p.; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 30)
    - Transitional Structure and the Units of Encoding, 18 pages; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 30)
      Notes, drafts regarding "...the system of transitinal-probability relationships between units in a language..." (morphemes, etc.).
    - The Varieties of Meaning, 1955; 3 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 30)
      Offprints from The Institute of Languages and Linguistics, Georgetown University, Monograph Number 8.
    - Voiceless Vowels Lecture, n.d.; 26 pages; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 30)
      Apparently a transcript of a lecture given in Texas. From folder: "Voiceless Vowels Project Incompl."
    - Wisconsin Archeological Society Talk, 1930, n.d.; 10 pp, 1 booklet; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 30)
      Partial draft, notes, etc. Includes "Outline of Examination" from the Harvard Medical School, Department of Psychiatry.
    - Stray Numbers: Iroquois-Catawba; S.E., n.d.; 14 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn, et al (Box 30)
      Notes, articles, etc. on stray numbers in Iroquois-Catawba.
    - Lounsbury Genealogy, n.d.; 2 item (Box 30)
      Some 18th and 19th Century ancestors of FGL. Includes text and diagrams.
    - Obituary for Robert Eugene Ritzenthaler, 1982; 5.0 p.; Lurie, Nancy Oestreich (Box 30)
      Reprint from American Anthropologist.
    - Magic Squares (Box 30)
      Assorted materials and notes on magic squares. Includes correspondence; annotated photocopies from The Complete Book of Magic and Witchcraft by Kathryn Paulsen, Signet Books, 1970; two photocopy pages from The Life of Cornelius Agrippa von Nettesheim by Henry Morley, Chapman and Hall, 1856; handwritten copy of a treatise by Muhammad ibn Muhammad in Arabic on magical numerical squares; assorted photocopies taken from a work in German; etc.
    - Maine History, 1998; 1 item (Box 30)
      A Special Issue devoted to Frank T. Siebert, Jr.
    - Bibliographies for language typology, comparative linguistics, phonology, etc., 1963-1965, n.d.; 19 pages; Martin, Samuel E., (Samuel Elmo), 1924-2009 (Box 30)
    - Tribus indigenas de Norte America, 8 pcs.; Murdock, George Peter, 1897-1985 (Box 30)
      Hand-colored maps; carbon of key to map; photographs of map showing culture areas, languages, and tribes.
    - Archaeological Method and Theory: Syllabus, 1994; 1 p; Neiman, Fraser (Box 30)
      Photocopy of computer-generated document.
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1970-1971; 2 items (Box 30)
      Concerned with term of address for a "step grandmother" and "Determining Who is a Jew."
    - Northeast Anthropology, 1994; 1 item (Box 30)
      Number 48-articles primarily on archeology.
    - Notes [on planetary tables, formulae, magic squares, etc.], 2.0 folders (Box 30)
    - Structural History: A Programmatic Synthesis of the Nomothetic and Idiographic Elements of Anthropological Studies, 41 pages; Nutini, Hugo G. (Box 30)
    - Oxford International Conference of Archaeo-Astronomy, n.d.; 6 pages (Box 30)
      List of participants (?) at the 2nd such conference.
    - Current Developments in Montague Grammar, n.d.; 5 pages; Partee, Barbara Hall (Box 31)
      Ditto handout.
    - The Massawomeck: Raiders and Traders into the Chesapeake Bay in the Seventeenth Century, 1991; 1 item; 11 pages; Pendergast, James F. (Box 31)
      Volume 81, Part 2 of Transactions of the American Philosophical Society. Includes photocopies of bibliography from Pendergast's An Iroquoian Nation.
    - Research proposals, n.d.; 16 pages; Pospisil, Leopold J. (Box 31)
      Regarding the investigation of legal systems.
    - Linguistic Stocks of American Indians North of Mexico, 1 item; Powell, J. W. (Box 31)
      Plate 1 from the BAE Seventh Annual Report.
    - Autochthonous American writing systems: The Aztec and Maya examples, 1983; 1 item; Prem, Hanns J., 1941-; Riese, Berthold (Box 31)
      Offprint from Writing in Focus, Mouton.
    - Proposal to save Aboriginal Languages, n.d.; 1 p (Box 31)
      Photocopy of newspaper article regarding the Native languages of Canada.
    - Quarterly Review of Archaeology (Box 31)
    - Reports from Anthropological Division, Geological Survey, Canada, 1913; 1 item (Box 31)
      Offprint. Includes A. A. Goldenweiser, "On Iroquois Work, 1913-1914."
    - Untitled handout on syntax, 1970; 2 pages; Robinson, J. (Box 31)
    - Coupe biogeographique et ethnobiologique de la peninsule Quebec-Labrador, 1964; 1 item; Rousseau, Jacques (Box 31)
      Offprint from Le Nouveau-Quebec: Contribution a l'etude de l'occupation humaine.
    - L'indien de la foret boreale, element de la formation ecologique, 1957; 1 item; Rousseau, Jacques (Box 31)
      Offprint from Royal Society of Canada (Societe Royale du Canada) Studia Varia.
    - La trame forestiere de l'histoire canadienne, 1962; 1 item; Rousseau, Jacques (Box 31)
      Published by Les editions des dix, Montreal.
    - Letters to Robert H. Lowie, 1965; 1 item; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939 (Box 31)
      Letters from Edward Sapir to Robert H. Lowie, including correspondence 1908-1938.
    - Book Reports, 1947; 14 pages; Schaedel, Richard P. (Box 31)
      On Elemente der Phonetik (Vietor) and Sounds of English (Sweet).
    - Reading lists for anthropology courses, n.d.; 7 pages; Scheffler, Hal W. (Box 31)
      Ditto of typed documents.
    - Skin and Fur Mosaics in Prehistoric and Modern Times, 1964; 1 item; Schuster, Carl, 1904-1969 (Box 31)
      Offprint from Festschrift for Ad. E. Jensen.
    - Magische Quadrate im islamischen Bereich Ihre Entlehnung ins Abendland im Mittelalter sowie ihre Vorstufen, Schuster, Von H. - S. (Box 31)
      Contains photocopies of Schuster and other printed materials in German pertaining to magic squares, number tables, astrological figures, etc.
    - Historical Linguistics, 1972; 49.0 p.; Shipley, William, 1921-2011 (Box 31)
      Typed manuscript. Chapter for Volume 8, Handbook of North American Indians.
    - Obituary, 1973; 1 item; Smith, Henry Lee (Box 31)
      Copy of "Linguistics Newsletter, SUNY at Buffalo."
    - The Boas Plan for American Indian Linguistics, 1968; 2 items; Stocking, George W., 1928- (Box 31)
      Mimeo of typed document. Includes letter to FGL from GWS.
    - Tanjii (Box 31)
    - The Cost of Bread, 1957; 1 item; Temple, Charles R. (Box 31)
      Mimeo of letter to Walter S. Rogers from CRT with heading "Institute of Current World Affairs."
    - Lewis H. Morgan and His Contemporaries, 1992; 1 item; Tooker, Elisabeth, 1927- (Box 31)
      Offprint from American Anthropologist, Vol. 94 with note to Floyd from Betty.
    - Map of North American Indian Languages, 1941; 1 item; Erminie Wheeler-Voegelin, 1903-1988; Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986 (Box 31)
    - Voiceless Vowels Notes, n.d.; ca. 75 pp, 1 spiral notebook (Box 31)
      Photocopies of published work, notes, analysis, etc. From folder: "Voiceless Vowels Project Incompl."
    - Myth turns bungling, villain Columbus into hero, 1989; 1 item; Weatherford, Jack (Box 31)
      Clipping from New Haven Register.
    - The strategic use of questions in court, 1984; 1 item; Woodbury, Hanni (Box 31)
      Offprint from Semiotica, Vol. 48.
    - Wulumu, Charlie Lya, 1956; 1 item (Box 31)
      Article about an Australian aboriginie in New Haven Register.
    - Graduate compositions in Anthropology and Linguistics, 1958, n.d.; 27 pages; Yale University. Department of Anthropology. (Box 31)
      Typed and handwritten documents.
    - Undergraduate compositions, 36.0 Item(s); Yale University. Department of Anthropology. (Box 31)
    - Comparison of Greek and Noh Dramas, 1939; 34 pages; Yokoyama [Lounsbury], Masako (Box 31)
      Term paper written for an English course.
    - Review of Sweet, Jesperson, and Pike, 1948; 53 pages; Yokoyama [Lounsbury], Masako (Box 31)
      A Critical Review of Henry Sweet's The Sounds of English..., Otto Jesperson's Lehrbuch der Phonetik, and Kenneth L. Pike's Phonetics. Includes typed and handwritten notes from Jesperson and Pike.
  - Indo-European (Box 32)
    - English Literature, n.d.; 1 notebook (2 folders) (Box 32)
    - An Axiomatic Approach to English Grammar, 1957; 2 pages; Joos, Martin (Box 32)
    - English lessons, n.d.; 6 items; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 32)
      Drafts for pedagogical materials.
    - History of the German Language, [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 32)
    - Icelandic Notes, [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 32)
    - Old High German and "MHD", [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 32)
    - Old Irish notes, n.d.; 9 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 32)
      Includes: Offprint of Myles Dillon, "On Three Passages in Lebor Na Huidre"; texts in [Old Irish] without translation; texts in English; mimeographed document on [Old Irish] phonology and syntax; class notes.
    - Russian Adjective and Noun Paradigms, 10 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 32)
    - Typescript of Das Lied von der Erde, [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 32)
    - Portuguese Time Expressions, n.d.; 5 pp; 8 slips; Wiesenthal, Andrew M. (Box 32)
      Typed document and handwritten English time expressions.
  - Iroquoian (Box 32-69)
    - Cayuga (Box 32-33)
      - Fieldnotes, n.d.; ca. 70 pages; Barbeau, Marius, 1883-1969 (Box 32)
        Photocopy of texts from fieldnotes.
      - An Iroquois Condolence Council for installing Cayuga chiefs in 1945, 1946; 1 item; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Box 32)
        Offprint of article from Journal of the Washington Academy of Sciences, Vol. 36, No. 4.
      - Alternating Weak and Strong Syllables in Cayuga Words, 1978, 1982; 2 items; Foster, Michael K. (Box 32)
        Photocopy of typed document and offprint from IJAL, Vol. 48, No. 1.
      - Cayuga text and analysis, 1989; 2 items; Foster, Michael K. (Box 32)
        Photocopy of typed document and letter to FGL. Includes sample and discussion of Foster's work on council speeches by Jake Thomas.
      - Formal Speaking on the Six Nations Reserve, 1969, n.d.; 2 items; Foster, Michael K. (Box 32)
        Research and dissertation proposals.
      - When Words Become Deeds, 1972; 1 item; Foster, Michael K. (Box 32)
        Handout for paper given at 1972 Conference on Iroquois Research.
      - Cayuga pronominal prefixes, n.d.; 15 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 32)
        Charts and discussion. Includes 1 page chart of Oneida prefixes.
      - Copies of Fieldnotes, 1948, 1960, n.d.; ca. 300 pages; 4 folders; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 32-33)
        Photocopies of fieldnotes from Mrs. Skye (mother of Howard Skye), Howard Skye, Alexander General, and Mrs. George Green.
      - Fieldnotes, Mrs. George Green, 1998, n.d.; 3 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 33)
        Fieldnotes, Mrs. George Green. Includes notebook, photocopy of notebook, and note from Bryan Gick regarding a recording.
      - Fieldnotes, Mrs. Skye and Mrs. George Green, 1948, 1960, n.d.; 3 items; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 33)
        Fieldnotes from Mrs. Skye (mother of Howard Skye), Howard Skye, Alexander General, and Mrs. George Green.
      - Text and translation from Nora Carrier, 21 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 33)
      - Texts from Alexander General, 1960, n.d.; 2 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 33)
        Two partially-used notebooks. Thanksgiving ceremony.
      - Texts from Alexander General, Mrs. George Green, and Howard Skye, 1960, n.d.; 3 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 33)
        Two partially-used notebooks.
      - Transcriptions from recordings by Alexander General, ca. 45 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 33)
      - Translation of text from Alexander General, 5 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 33)
    - Cherokee (Box 34-36)
      - Cherokee paradigms, n.d.; ca. 100 pages; Anonymous (Box 34)
      - Cherokee publications, 1828, 1962-1963, n.d.; 7 items; Anonymous (Box 34)
        Includes: Cherokee Phoenix, Cherokee Speaker, Cherokee Hymns (in the syllabary), The Swiss Peasant (in the syllabary), "Cherokee Reading Grammar" (mimeo manuscript in the syllabary with English glosses), and "Cherokee Paradigms" (mimeo manuscript).
      - Cherokee texts, n.d.; 1 item; Anonymous (Box 34)
        Includes interlinear and free English translations. Photocopy of typed manuscript.
      - Cherokee vocabulary, n.d.; 13 pages; Anonymous (Box 34)
      - English-Nottowegh-Cherokee word list ..., n.d.; 2 items; Anonymous (Box 34)
        English-Nottowegh-Cherokee word list attached to the journal of Major John Norton, 1816. Include photocopy of original and typed transcription.
      - Miscellaneous notes, 1974, n.d.; 4 items; Anonymous (Box 34)
      - Notes on interviews, 1953; 1 item; Anonymous (Box 34)
        Notes on interviews with North Carolina Cherokees. Includes some words and phrases in Cherokee with English translation.
      - Vocabulary, n.d.; 10 pages; Anonymous (Box 34)
        From folder: "Manes."
      - Cherokee Lessons, n.d.; 117 pages; Bushyhead, Robert; Cook, William (Box 34)
        Related materials
        Audio recordings corresponding to this text are available in digital format in Series VII of this collection.
        Preliminary draft, photocopy of typed manuscript
      - Dissertation notes, 1971, 1973, n.d.; 13 items; Cook, William (Box 34)
        Grant proposal, correspondence, etc. Includes photocopy of draft introduction.
      - Morphology and Syntax of North Carolina Cherokee, 1974-1975; 2 folders; Cook, William (Box 34)
        Photocopy of draft of dissertation. Includes comments by Rufus S. Hendon and letter to FGL from Cook.
      - Story of the Cherokee Bible, 1899; 1 item; Foster, Geo. E., (George Everett), 1849-1917 (Box 34)
        Ithaca, NY: Democrat Press.
      - Powell schedule for Eastern Cherokee, 1885; ca. 145 pages; Gatschet, Albert S., (Albert Samuel), 1832-1907 (Box 34)
        Photocopy of Bureau of American Ethnology, manuscript 390.
      - Vocabulary, n.d.; 5 pages; Gatschet, Albert S., (Albert Samuel), 1832-1907 (Box 34)
        Photocopy of BAE manuscript 4904
      - Words and Geographic Names from the Cheroki Language, 1886; 7 pages; Gatschet, Albert S., (Albert Samuel), 1832-1907 (Box 34)
        Photocopy of BAE manuscript 387.
      - The Cheroki an Iroquoian Language, 1887, 1973; 77 pages; Hewitt, J. N. B., (John Napoleon Brinton), 1859-1937 (Box 34)
        Photocopy of typed manuscript, BAE manuscript 447. Includes letter to FGL from Blair Rudes.
      - Cherokee, Eastern-fieldnotes, n.d.; 1 item; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 35)
        Consultants identified. Some consultants are from Oklahoma (Nancy Morgan, 3-6-07).
      - Cherokee Fieldnotes, n.d.; 12 items; 3 folders; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 35)
        Stenographers notebooks from FGL's Oklahoma fieldwork.
      - Cherokee notes, n.d.; ca. 60 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 35)
        Vocabulary, some text, analysis.
      - Cherokee Phonology, n.d.; 8.0 p.; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 35)
      - Fieldnotes-original and photocopies, 3 items; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 35)
        Original and photocopies. Two stenographers notebooks--one is identified externally as Cherokee, but the consultant is identified as "Blue Jacket (Wyandot). The two notebooks are copied side-by-side on 8 1/2 x 11 paper.
      - Fieldnotes-photocopies, n.d.; 3 folders; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 35-36)
        Fieldnotes-photocopies of FGL's Oklahoma notebooks.
      - Miscellaneous notes, 1888, n.d.; ca. 30 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 36)